THE CAPITAL JURY PROJECT RECORDS (APAP196) 1941-2011
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Death Penalty Research, 1968-2004; 5; 18
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 26, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 27, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 28, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 29, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 30, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 31, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 32, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 33, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 34, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Court Transcript Vol. 35, 1991 January-Febraury (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Appeal Transcript Vol. 6, 1991 August 09 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Appeal Transcript Vol. 7, 1991 August 09 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Appeal Transcript Vol. 8, 1991 August 09 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Appeal Transcript Vol. 9, 1991 August 09 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Appeal Transcript Vol. 10, 1991 August 09 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Appeal Transcript Vol. 11, 1991 August 09 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Email Containging Transcript of Appeal, 2002 September 05 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Trepal, George v. of Florida Research Printouts and Notes, 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Trepal, George Sentencing Transcript Florida *restricted*, 1991 February -07 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - The United States Law Week Opinions Announced May 30, 1991, 1991 May 30 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Utah Folder Caselaw Research, Undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Van Tran, Heck Case Information Sheet Tennessee *restricted*, Undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Van Tran CJP caselaw research, Undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Voire Dire Sheets, Undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Waddell, James Howard v. State of North Carolina, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Weeks, Lonnie Federal Petition, Correspondence from Sidley + Austin re; Weeks v. Virginia, 1995 May 17 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Witherspoon v. Illinois 391 U.S. 510 Certiorari to Supreme Court of IL, 1968 June 03 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Witt v. Wainwright 470 v.s. 1039, 1985 March 05 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Wright, Dwanye v. Commonwealth of Virigina Research Printouts, Undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Wyoming Folder Caselaw Research, Undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
- Publications, 1975-2006; 6; 2
  Arranged Chronologically.
  This series contains publications produced from the data collected in the CJP as well as other publications. Some 78 articles and book chapters based on the CJP data have been published and the CJP has served as the basis for 19 doctoral dissertations and theses.
  - "A Comparison of the Work of Thorsten Sellin and Isaac Ehrlich on the Different Effect of Capital Punishment" by David C. Baldus and James W.L. Cole, 1975 December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Executions Seen Selling into Violence" by Jean Dietz, 1980 August 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Arbitrariness and Discrimination Under Post-Furman Capital Statues" by William J. Bowers and Glenn Pierce, 1980 October (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Deciding Who Dies" by Stephen Gillers and Other Death Penalty Research, 1980 November; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Executions in America" - Draft by Henry Schwarzchild, 1982; 1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Executions in the United States, 1608-1987: The Espy File" by M. Watt Espy and John Ortiz Smykla (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Female Offenders on Death Row, Articles by Victor L. Streib, 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford v. Kentucky, 106 L Ed 2d 306, 1989 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Capital Punishment of Female Offenders Articles by Victor L. Streib, 1989-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "The Adventures of an Abolitionist: 13 Years Against Executions" by Neil D. Hulkower, 1990 April (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Californians Want an Alternate to the Death Penalty" By William J. Bowers LA Times Op Ed Article, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "The Death Penalty's Shaky Support" by William J. Bowers NY Times Article Including Correspondence and Related Research, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Massachusetts Voters Want an Alternative to the Death Penalty" by William J. Bowers, 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "New Yorkers Want an Alternative to the Death Penalty: Executive Summary of a New York Summary Conducted March 1-4, 1991" by Bowers, William J. and Vandiver, Margaret, 1991 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Nebraskans Want an Alternative to the Death Penalty" by William J. Bowers and Margaret Vandiver, 1991 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "The Capital Juror Project: Background and Research Design"- CJP #1 by William J. Bowers and Magaret Vandiver, 1991 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Death Penalty Attitudes of Prospective Capital Jurors: The Indiana Voir Dire Project (A Preliminary Report)" - CJP #3 Joseph L. Hoffman, 1991 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Models of Decision Making in Capital Cases: Preliminary Findings" - CJP #2 by Marla Sandys, 1991 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Lottery od Life: Who Gets to Death Row" Transcript and Enid Harlow Correspondence, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Death Penalty Bill Raises Issues of Effects, Ethics" by Peter J. Howe and "The Govenor's Quick Fix for Murders by William J. Bowers, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "In Their Own Words: How Capital Jurors Explain Their Life or Death Sentencing Decisions" - CJP #6 by William J. Bowers and Margaret Vandiver, 1992 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "In Their Own Words: How Capital Jurors Explain Their Life or Death Sentencing Decisions" - CJP #7 by William J. Bowers, Margaret Vandiver, and Patricia H. Dugan, 1992 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "National Capital Jury Preliminary Results from South Carloina" CJP #10 by Theodore Esienberg, 1992 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Jurors Response to the Defendants Testimony or Lack Thereof" - CJP #9 by William J. Bower and Heather S. MacAskill, 1992 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Tables for the Panel on the Capital Jury Project- In Progress: A Special Focus on Pre-Trial Publicity"- CJP #11 by Marla Sandys, 1992 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Proof Beyond a Resonable Doubt: A Review of Jurors Thoughts"- CJP #8 by William J. Bowers and Andrea L. Waldo, 1992 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "The Life or Death Decisions of Capital Jurors: Preliminary Findings from Kentucky"- CJP #4 by Marla Sandys, 1992 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Capital Punishment and the Myth [illusion] of Deterrence" Draft for the Globe by William J. Bowers, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Case Study: The Vanishing and Reappearing Penalty Trial"- CJP #15 by John Lamberth, 1993 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "In Their Own Words How Capital Jurors Explain their Life or Death Sentencing Decisions"- CJP #12 by William J. Bowers and Patricia H. Dugan, 1993 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "National Capital Jury Preliminary Results from South Carloina" CJP #14 by Theodore Esienberg, 1993 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Discretion in Capital Sentencing: Guided or Misguided? - CJP #13 by James Luginbuhl, 1993 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Themes of Moral Responsibility in the Sentencing Decisions of Capital Jurors - CJP #16 by Joesph Hoffmann, 1993 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - The Capital Jury Project: Working Papers to Date, 1993 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Critical Issues in Capital Jury Decision Making Preliminary Findings" -CJP #18 by William J. Bowers amd Patricia H. Dugan, 1993 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Cross- Overs Capital Jurors Who First Believe the Defendant Deserves to Die (Live) and then Vote for Life (Death) by Marla Sandys, 1993 October 30; 1994 June (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Aggravating Circumstances and Capital Punishment Law: Rhetoric and Real Reforms" By James R. Acker and C.S. Lanier, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Capital Murder From Benefit of Clergy to Bifurcated Trials: Narrowing the Class of Offenses Punishable by Death" by James R. Acker and C.S. Lanier, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Capital Punishment and Contemporary Values: People's Misgivings and the Courts Misconceptions" by William Bowers, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "The Demensions of Capital Murder" by Jamess R/ acker and C.S. Lanier, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "Doing the Devil's Work: Toward Model Death Penalty Legislation by James Acker and C.S. Lanier, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Parsing the Lexicon of Death: Aggravating Factors in Capital Sentencing Statues" by James R. Acker and C.S. Lanier, 1994 March-1994 April (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - "Massachusetts Citizens Punishment Preferences for First Degree Murder: Executive Summary of a Massachusetts Survey Conducted September 16-21, 1994" by Bowers, William J. and Dugan, Patricia H., 1994 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "In Fairness and Mercy: Statutory Mitigating Factors in Capital Punishment Laws" by James R. Acker and Charles S. Lanier, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "A New Look at Public Opinion on Capital Punishment: What Citizens and Legislators Prefer" by William J. Bowers, Margarate J. Vandier, and Patricia H. Dugan, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Violence, Representation and Responsibility in Capital Trials: The View from the Jury" by Sarat, Austin, 1995 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "Jurors Ignore, Misunderstood Instructions by Scott Burgins, 1995 May (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Early Research for William J. Bowers Book on Wrongful Death/Executions *Restricted*, 1995 November 22; 1997 January 16; Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "Matters of Life and Death: The Sentencing Provisions in Capital Punishment Statues" by James R. Acker and Charles S. Lanier, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Symposium: The Capital Jury Project" Indiana University School of Law-Bloomington, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "The Capital Jury: Is it Tilted Toward Death?" by William J. Bowers, 1996 March (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Judicature "The Capital Jury: is it Tilted Toward Death?" by William J. Bowers, 1996 March; Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - "Capital Punishment of Female Offenders: Present Female Death Row Inmates and Death Sentences and Executions of Female Offenders January 1, 1973 to June 30, 1996" by Victor L. Streib, 1996 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - The Pernicious Myth of Early Release from Prison for Convinced First Degree Murderers Not Sentences to Death" by Bowers, William J. Steiner, Benjamin D., 1996 July (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - "Race in the Jury Room: A Preliminary Ananlysis of Cases from the Capital Jury Project" by Margaret Vandier, 1997 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - "Testimony Presented to the Massachusetts State Legislature Regarding a Bill to Reinsate Capital Punishment" by William J. Bowers and Margaret Vandier, 1997 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - "Anti-Death Penalty Votes wer e Activated in the December 9th Primary: Executive Summary of December 9 Exit Poll Results by Bowers, William J., Steiner, Benjamin D., and Hill, BJ, 1997 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - "Women and Criminal Justice" Published by Haworth Press, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - "The Parole of Capital, First Degree and Second Degree Murderers: A Survey of State Parole Boards-Pilot Study Conducted October 1997- March 1998" by Steiner, Benjamin D., Biringer, Laura A., and Bowers, William J, 1998 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - "Foreclosed Impartilaity in Capital Sentencing: Juror's Predispositons, Guilt Trial Experience, and Premature Decision Making" by William J. Bowers, Marla Sandys and Benjamin D. Steiner, 1998 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - "Folk Knowledge as Legal Action: Death Penalty Judgements and the Tenant of Early Release in a Culture of Mistrust and Punitiveness" by Benjamin D. Steiner, Austin Sarat, and William J. Bowers, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - "Integrating Base Rate Data in Violence Risk Assessments at Capital Sentencing" by Mark D. Cunningham and Thomas J. Reidy, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Unamerican Activities: Death Penalty Abolition Efforts" by John F. Galliher, 1999 January 5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Death by Default: An Empirical Demonstration of False and Forced Choices in Capital Sentencing" by William J. Bowers and Benjamin D. Steiner, 1999 February (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Death by Default: An Empirical Demonstration of False and Forced Choices in Capital Sentencing" by William J. Bowers and Benjamin D. Steiner, 1999 February (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "The Capital Jury Project in Tennessee: A Comparison with Findings from Other States" by Lisa King and Margaret Vandier, 1999 November (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Capital Punishment and the Evolving Standards of Civilization" by Gardner Hanks and Craig Hemmens with Kate King Preface by John Adams, 1999 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Declaring Life at the Crossroads of Death: Victims Anti-Death Penalty Views amd Prosecutors' Charging Decisions by Wayne and A. Logan, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "When Balance and Fairness Collide: An Argument for Execution Impact Evidence in Capital Trials" by Wayne A. Logan, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "New Hampshire Citizens' Criminal Justice Attitudes and Punishment Preferences" by Bowers, William J. and Di Trolio, Elisa, 2000 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Rebecca Leathlean Letter to Northeastern University Press Regarding her Book, Sentenced to Die: A Controversial History of the Death Penalty, 2000 June 16 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Proposed Book Outline and Introduction by John M. Shipman Jr., 2000 July 20 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "A View From Inside: Inmate Attitudes on the Death Penalty" Author Unknown, 2000 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Second Thougths: Americans' Views on Death Penalty at the Turn of the Century" by Samuel R. Gross and Pheobe Ellsworth, 2000 November (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "The Perils of Public Opinion" by Deborah W. Denno, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "A View From Inside: What Prison Inmates Can Tell Us About Death Penalty Opinion" Author Unknown with William J. Bowers Suggestions, 2001 February 21 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Death Sentencing In Black and White: An Empirical Analysis of the Role of Juror's Race and Jury Racial Composition" by William J. Bowers, Benjamin D. Steiner, and Marla Sandys, 2001 February (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Apres Apprendi" Published in Federal Sentencing Reporter by Nancy J. King and Susan R. Klein, 2001 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "How Jurors Decide on Death: Guilt is Overwhelming; Aggravation Requires Death; and Mitigation is no Excuse" by Ursula Bentele and William J. Bowers [1 of 2], 2001 June 29 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "How Jurors Decide on Death: Guilt is Overwhelming; Aggravation Requires Death; and Mitigation is no Excuse" by Ursula Bentele and William J. Bowers [2 of 2], 2001 June 29 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Brian Hoffamn and Ronald Orr Draft on CJP- South Carolina, 2001 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "How Jurors Decide on Death: Guilt is Overwhelming; Aggravation Requires Death; and Mitigation is no Excuse" by Ursula Bentele and William J. Bowers, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Does Capital Punishment Have a Detterent Effect? New Evidence From Post-Moratorium Panel Data*" by Hashem Dezhbakhsh, Paul H. Rubin, and Joanna M. Shepard, 2002 January (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Misguided Discretion: The Hydraulic Process Model and Juror Sentencing in Capital Trials by Bryan Edelman- Discretion Draft, 2002 October 7; 2002 October 19 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Early Research for William J. Bowers Book on Wrongful Death/Executions *Restricted*, 2003 January 7; Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Judicature Publications, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Too Young to be Executed: An Empirical Examination of Community Conscience and Death Penalty From the Perspectives of Capital Jurors" Publications Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "Too Young to be Executed" Publication Correspondence from Boston University Law Review, 2004 February (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "Capital Jurors as the Litmus Test of Vommunity Conscience for Juvenile Death Penalty" by Michael E. Antonio, Benjamin D. Fleury-Steiner, Valerie P. Hans, and William J. Bowers, 2004 May-2004 June (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "Too Young for the Death Penalty: An Empirical Examination of Community Conscience and the Juvenile Death Penalty From the Perspective of Capital Jurors" by William J. Bowers, Benjamin Fleury-Steiner, ,Valerie P. Hans, and Michael E. Antonio, 2004 June (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "Crossing Racial Boundaries: A Closer Look at the Roots of Racial Bias in Capital Sentencing when the Defendant is Black and the Victim is White" by William J. Bowers, Marla Sandys, and Thomas Brewer, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Publication Correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "The Capital Jury Project: Rationale, Design, and Prospects" By William J. Bowers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "The Capital Sentencing Decision: Guided Discretion, Reasoned Moral Judgement, or Legal Fiction" By William J. Bowers, Benjamin D. Fleury-Steiner and Michael E. Antonio, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "Family Histories of Death Row Inmates" From Grant Application and MR; mv-12/20/90; mv 11/20/91, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "The Inadequacy of Capital Sentencing Instructions" by James Luginbuhl and Julie Howe, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "Impediments to Mitigation in Capital Senetecning" Attachment B by Bowers, William J and Sandys, Marla, Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Judge: Death Penalty Kills Innocent" by Adam Gorlick, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - "Race and the Punishment of Criminal Violence" by Bowers, William J and Sandys, Marla, Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - William J. Bower' Writings, Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Subject Files, 1941-1996; 7; 17
  The subject files are some of the earilest material in the collection. The subject files came from the filing cabinets of Dr. Bowers at Northeastern University. The material spans a great deal of interests and topics such as Amnesty International and Lethal Injection.
  - Abstracts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abuse, 1977; 1983; 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abuse 2, 1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Academy of Criminal Justice Science Annual Meeting, 1996 March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Access to Post Secondary Education: Phase I, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alabama Death Row, 1977-1980; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alcohol-Drinking Age Project, Outlines, Correspondence, 1979-1980; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1994; 1995; 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Amnesty International Annual General Meeting, 1991 June (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amnesty International Meeting Information, 1990 August- 1991 January (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Amnesty International Northeast Regional Conference, Boston, 1992 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Amnesty International Northeast Regional Conference, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Amnesty International Student Conference on Death Penalty, 1989 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Amnesty International Survey, 1986 May; 1990 March 12; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Amnesty International USA, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Amnesty Texas News Articles, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Announcement of Candlelight Vigil in Memory of Junior Fernandez, 1990 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ashburn, Randy's Letter to the Jury Study Team Regarding Seventh Circuit's to FREE, 1992 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Arbitrariness & Determination - Most Updated, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Arb. 9 Discrim. - Galleys, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Arbitrariness & Discrimination, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Arizona Corrections Cases, 1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bath, Amanda Joy Correspondence and Amnesty International Information, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bay State Lifers' and Long Termers' Group Bay State Correctional Center Correspondence, 1994 December 15; 1994 December 16; Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bibliography- Public Opinion, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Boston Fenway, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Boston Globe Poll on Death Penalty Attitudes, 1990 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Boston and Seattle Conferences Publications and Resources, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Boston Urban Database, 1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Boston Urban Database (BUD), 1985; 1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Boston Urban Database (BUD), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The Bloomington Voice, 1992 March; 1992 November (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bridges to Life Fact Sheet, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Brady, James- Arson, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Brown versus Wainwright, 1980; 1981; Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Brutilization Bibliography, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Budrevis NIJ, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Cameras in Court Report, 1989-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Cameras in Court Report, 1989-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Cameras in Court Report, 1989-1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cameras in Court Report, 1989-1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Campus Unrest in Comparative Perspective" Original Coversheet, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Capital Punishment as Case Study in the Incremental Evaluation of Guided Discretion by William J. Bowers and Glenn L. Pierce, 1979 November (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Capital Punishment Book, 1981-1982; 1984; 1986-1988; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Capital Punishment Book, 1981-1982; 1984; 1986-1988; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Capital Punishment Media, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Capital Punishment Vignette Project, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Carl S. Ell Student Center and Student Activities Handbook, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - CASR Projects and Proposals, 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Center for Survey Research Newsletters, 1986; 1988 May; 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chapter on National Punishment from National Survey of State Laws, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Child Abuse, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Civil Liberties Union of Massachusetts (CLUM) Committee, 1990-1991; 1993; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Civil Rights, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Citizens United for the Rehabilitation of Errants (CURE), 1986 February; 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Clemency - Raymond Stoue, 1983 February 22 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Comment on Barton - Hauser Exchange, 1971 February (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Comment on "The Deterrent Effect of Capital Punishment: Ehrlich and his Cities" Comment by Jon K. Peck, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Commonwealth of Massachusetts Election Statistics, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Controception - Constance Nathanson, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Conyers Testimony, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Connecticut Network to Abolish the Death Penalty Newsletter, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Cordray, David, Northeastern University Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Data Acquisition, NSF, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: NSF Info Requests, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)